<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FTB on OpenVerify Courses</title>
    <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/tags/ftb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FTB on OpenVerify Courses</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/tags/ftb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FTB Item and Complete Prediction Result Interface</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/ports/00_ftb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/ports/00_ftb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ftb-item&#34;&gt;FTB item&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FTB item is the core data structure of branch prediction blocks in Xiangshan. It stores the information needed to generate a branch prediction block. When BPU performs predictions, the initial branch prediction block is first generated from a read-out FTB item. Then, this branch prediction block is passed to subsequent predictors, which read and modify the information to generate the final prediction result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, to understand the structure of a branch prediction block, we first need to understand the structure of an FTB item. An FTB item corresponds to a branch prediction block, and its general structure is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FTB Feature List</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/feature/02_ftbfeature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/feature/02_ftbfeature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;feature-list&#34;&gt;Feature List&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Support FTB entry storage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Support basic prediction result output and meta information output for the s2, s3 channels&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Support update request response, updating internal FTB entries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FTB Branch Predictor</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/03_ftb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/03_ftb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-ftb&#34;&gt;Introduction to FTB&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FTB is the third sub-predictor of the Xiangshan BPU, and it can also get the outputs of uFTB and TAGE-SC together. In the input interface of FTB, the s1 channel contains the basic prediction results of uFTB, and the s2 and s3 channels are filled with only one group of signals, &lt;code&gt;br_taken_mask&lt;/code&gt;, by TAGE-SC, without the basic prediction results generated by the FTB entry. The function of FTB is to provide basic prediction results for the s2 and s3 channels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
