<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Subpredictor on OpenVerify Courses</title>
    <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/tags/subpredictor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Subpredictor on OpenVerify Courses</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/tags/subpredictor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TAGE-SC Branch Predictor</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/02_tage_sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/02_tage_sc/</guid>
      <description>Introduction TAGE-SC is the primary predictor for conditional branches in the Kunming Lake architecture, classified as an Accurate Predictor (APD). TAGE-SC can be seen as two relatively independent components: the prediction part TAGE and the verification part SC.&#xA;The Tagged Geometric History Length Predictor (TAGE) utilizes multiple prediction tables with different history lengths to exploit extensive branch history information. TAGE predicts whether a branch instruction will be taken or not taken.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ITTAGE Branch Predictor</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/04_ittage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/04_ittage/</guid>
      <description>Function Introduction For general conditional branch instructions, only predicting whether to jump (taken) or not (not taken) is needed. However, for indirect jumps, such as call/jump instructions, it is necessary to predict where to jump to (Target). In order to make TAGE support predicting jump addresses, ITTAGE (Indirect Target TAGE) was introduced.&#xA;The main difference between ITTAGE and TAGE is that in the T0 and Tn tables, Target PC data is added.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
