<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenVerify Courses – Docs</title>
    <link>https://xs-mlvp.github.io/xs-bpu/en/tags/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on OpenVerify Courses</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://xs-mlvp.github.io/xs-bpu/en/tags/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Feature List</title>
      <link>https://xs-mlvp.github.io/xs-bpu/en/docs/feature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xs-mlvp.github.io/xs-bpu/en/docs/feature/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Feature List&lt;/strong&gt; in hardware verification lists various functions and characteristics of the design that need to be verified. Before starting verification, we generally list the features of the design to clarify which features need to be verified in this task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To verify a feature in the feature list, we will build the necessary test points for this feature and write test cases to cover these test points. Therefore, the feature list is not only a description of the features of the design to be verified but also a guide for our verification direction and a simple summary of the verification task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this verification, we provide a basic feature list for each verification task (i.e., the top-level BPU and each sub-predictor), which only covers the basic functions of the corresponding module. In your verification, you must ensure that this verification covers these features. Additionally, you can supplement features not covered in the list to ensure the final delivery quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this document section, you only need to refer to the document corresponding to the module you will verify.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
