<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xiangshan on OpenVerify Courses</title>
    <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/tags/xiangshan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xiangshan on OpenVerify Courses</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/tags/xiangshan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BPU Top Module</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/00_bpu_top/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/00_bpu_top/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The overall function and structure of the BPU top level have been roughly described in previous documents. For those verifying the BPU top level, a more detailed description might be needed. Due to the many functions of the BPU top level, this section divides the BPU into several major functional points for further description. However, since there are too many details at the BPU top level, further details need to be understood by referring to the code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Important Structures and Interface Documentation</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/ports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This document will describe the important structures and external interfaces in the BPU, with a description granularity that delves into the code level. The structures described in the document will be consistent with the Chisel version of the Xiangshan branch prediction unit code, and the signal structures and names also come from the Chisel version code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This document is intended for those who have already understood the basic design of the Xiangshan branch prediction unit and want to delve into the signal details. You can selectively read according to the content needed for verification or refer to it at any time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Submodule Documentation</title>
      <link>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://open-verify.cc/xs-bpu/en/docs/modules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This section of the documentation will provide a detailed introduction to each module of the Xiangshan Branch Prediction Unit, including the BPU top-level and five sub-predictors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In each module&amp;rsquo;s documentation, we will provide a detailed explanation of the module&amp;rsquo;s role in the Xiangshan Branch Prediction Unit, as well as the module&amp;rsquo;s algorithm principles, structure, and timing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Students responsible for verifying a specific module should read the corresponding documentation thoroughly and understand it in conjunction with the code. Other documents can also be read to help you understand the overall functionality of the Xiangshan Branch Prediction Unit. During the understanding process, you may need to constantly review the basic design concepts and interface signals described in previous documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
